# **JAMES PISTELL**

#### JamesPistell.com | (C) 315-576-5094 | jamespistell@gmail.com

JamesPistell.com Skype: james.pistell

## **Professional Summary**

Resourceful Online Marketing Professional with 4 years of experience developing and implementing digital marketing and advertising campaigns. Have designed and developed websites and digital marketing strategies for clients and personal use. A forward-thinking Marketing Guru who creates landing pages and tracking systems, while analyzing ROI and conversion to adjust marketing messaging. Moonlights as a commissioned officer in the Army National Guard.

## **Skills**

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- Google Analytics
- Google AdWords
- Amazon Seller Central

- Digital marketing
- Campaign Optimization
- Internet and E-mail Marketing?
- Marketing Automation Software
- Web Hosting

# **Work History**

## **PPC & SEM Manager**

Honeyguide PPC – Rochester, NY

09/2013 to Current

- Managed PPC accounts in Google AdWords, Bing AdCenter & Amazon Seller Central
- Implemented strategies to grow social media accounts on Instagram by 1000%
- Wrote custom event triggers in JavaScript that integrated with Google Analytics API to track customer engagement and increase conversion rates

## Platoon Leader United States Army National Guard – Geneva, NY

12/2011 to Current

- Platoon Leader in the rank of 1st Lieutenant in an Army National Guard cavalry scout troop located in Geneva, NY
- Accounted for more than \$25 million in deployable and installation equipment
- Directly responsible for the training and leadership of 25 subordinates

#### Webmaster Self Employed – Rochester, NY

01/2010 to Current

- Manages a portfolio of personal and client websites as well as their web hosting services. Responsible for maintaining their uptime, security, billing, PPC, SEO, web design and development
- Worked closely with social media clients on WordPress blogs and social media marketing.
- Used site analytics and metrics to define and monitor success.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science: History SUNY Brockport - Brockport, NY 2011

Minor in Military Science

Associate of Science: Liberal Arts
Monroe Community College - Brighton, NY

2008

# **Accomplishments**

- Created an automotive owners manuals database called JustGiveMeTheManual.com. Was featured on several popular automotive blogs including Jalopnik, TheTruthAboutCars & Edmunds
- Maintains several "for fun" social media accounts with tens of thousands of followers on Facebook & Instagram
- Platoon Leader adept at briefing and training more than 25 service personnel. Expertise in reconnaissance tasks,